Since you've studied the stocks in your universe now for a while,
由于你已经对股票池中的股票研究了一段时间
you might already know which stock has been performing the best.
你可能已经知道哪支股票业绩一直最佳
Let's call it New Digital Corporation.
假设是 New Digital 公司
At this point, you may want to put all your money in New Digital stock.
目前 你可能想要将所有资金都投入到 New Digital 股票中
But let's say you do this and New Digital stock keeps increasing in value for a while,
假设你这么做了 并且 New Digital 股票一直上涨了一段时间
but suddenly drops to half the price you purchased that.
但是忽然下跌到买入价的一半
Since you used all your money to buy the stock,
因为你用所有资金买入了这支股票
you just lost half your money.
所以损失了所有资金
Ouch! What if instead you put
天啊如果你将一半资金
half your money in New Digital and half your money in Big Pharma Company?
投入到 New Digital 股票中 将另一半投入到 Big Pharma 股票中呢？
Intuitively, this seems like it could smooth out the dips and value of your investment,
直观地讲 这么做似乎可以抹平投资波动性
because New Digital could start doing well when it launches a new tech product,
因为当 New Digital 发布新的科技产品后 业绩可能会好起来
while Big Pharma recovers from a failed drug trial.
而 Big Pharma 能从药物试验失败中缓过来
Big pharma might start doing well when it's research arm,
当 Big Pharma 的研究团队
deliver several new promising candidate drugs,
公布几个有前景的药物时 可能业绩会升上来
while New Digital struggles during a change in management.
而 New Digital 因为管理层变动而业绩下滑
What we've done here is reduced our portfolio risk by diversifying our portfolio.
我们通过分散投资降低了投资组合的风险
But why not keep spreading our money into more and more stocks?
但是为何不将资金分散到更多的股票上呢？
Can we reduce our portfolio risk indefinitely?
能够无限地降低投资组合风险吗？
If all the sources of risk are independent,
如果所有的风险来源都是独立的
we could in theory,
从理论上来讲
reduce risk to zero by spreading our money between more and more stocks.
我们可以通过将资金分散到越来越多的股票上 使风险降为零
This would be the case if each company is only
如果每个公司仅受它自己的独立风险来源影响
subject to its own independent sources of risk,
并且没有影响所有公司的同一风险
and there are no risks common to all companies.
那么这种理论是成立的
Risks specific to individual companies is called idiosyncratic risk or specific risk.
特定于单个公司的风险称为特质风险或个别风险
However, in the real world,
但是 在现实中
all companies are subject to common sources of risk that
所有公司都受到相同风险的影响
affect the entire economy such as the risks of inflation,
这些风险会影响到整个经济 例如通货膨胀
recession, or change in interest rates or GDP.
经济萧条 利率或 GDP 变化
Risk attributable to market-wide sources is called market risk or systematic risk.
因市场原因导致的风险称为市场风险或系统性风险
Let's see if we can quantify this risk and
接下来我们将学习如何量化风险
find some guidelines for how to allocate our money.
以及如何分配资金